[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339743", "question": "Who was the only constant member of the rock band \"The Byrds\"?", "answer": "Jim McGuinn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af69", "question": "During what war did thousands of Americans invade the shores of Normandy?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd662dea5bfecdd737e0849", "question": "What percentage of Americans can trace at least one ancestor to Ellis Island?", "answer": "40 percent", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc22b6ce05a3942286f1a", "question": "The powerful mineral vibranium is mined from which fictional country?", "answer": "Wakanda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0e4", "question": "Which pasta is shaped like a short tube?", "answer": "Ditalini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dfe509616e6c6d4eba4fc", "question": "Who is the lead singer for the American rock band Pearl Jam?", "answer": "Eddie Vedder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133927f", "question": "In seasons 12 and 13 of the TV show \"Big Brother\", what competitor is associated with \"crybernating\"?", "answer": "Rachel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a2", "question": "Who is known as Eminem?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a17a", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Next\"?", "answer": "The Sensational Alex Harvey Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb21", "question": "In 1990, what did the World Health Organization officially remove from its list of \"mental illnesses\"?", "answer": "Homosexuality", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008d65cf842fa4c4ba96a9", "question": "Who was Liverpool's captain when they won their first European Cup final in 1977?", "answer": "Emlyn Hughes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5b8", "question": "What Miss America Pageant winner turned in her tiara on July 23, 1984?", "answer": "Vanessa Williams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909d0acbb53d1af658864fd", "question": "What car did Frank buy for himself for Christmas in Season 6 of the TV show \"It\u2019s Always Sunny in Philadelphia\"?", "answer": "Lamborghini Countach", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c1de877e98cb9777897f", "question": "What was the first cave in the world to be designated a national park?", "answer": "Wind Cave", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58dba59f874c93a3298b2152", "question": "What talk show has Chris Hardwick hosted on AMC immediatley following the TV show \"The Walking Dead\"?", "answer": "The Talking Dead", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e928b24f84e0b9f9ffcb", "question": "Seretse Khama was the first President of which country?", "answer": "Botswana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4e2", "question": "What is Japanese sake made from?", "answer": "Rice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc79", "question": "What company's famous plaid pattern is called \"novacheck\"?", "answer": "Burberry's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa6", "question": "Who wrote the book \"The Red and the Green\"?", "answer": "Iris Murdoch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8f4", "question": "What country borders both of the world's only two nations with square flags?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2d", "question": "What dessert consists of beaten egg whites, sugar, and cream of tartar?", "answer": "Meringue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c476", "question": "What type of animal was the first ever to be cloned from an adult cell?", "answer": "A sheep", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbd9", "question": "In 2003, who became the first Latin\u00adAmerican to hit 500 career home runs in Major League Baseball?", "answer": "Sammy Sosa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59029ef1cad1ec93f27df759", "question": "Above 5,000 ft, coffee beans tend to develop a high level of what?", "answer": "Acidity", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ed", "question": "Into which bay does the Golden Gate Strait lead?", "answer": "San Francisco Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7361aeec85e375820b259", "question": "Where did Dr. Samuel Mudd serve prison after he was convicted for his involvement in President Lincoln's assassination?", "answer": "Fort Jefferson in the Dry Tortugas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e6bba0fb6c85e9e634ff57", "question": "Managua is the capital of which Central American country?", "answer": "Nicaragua", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b323727bf195a31e15d73c2", "question": "Who directed the 1980 film \"Ordinary People\"?", "answer": "Robert Redford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133982e", "question": "What country singer was born Virginia Hensley?", "answer": "Patsy Cline", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990f939fa5fdd6dd25324f5", "question": "What film did John Wayne win his only Oscar for?", "answer": "True Grit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a6", "question": "What movie starred Mel Gibson as William Wallace?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c819", "question": "In what part of the body would you find amniotic fluid?", "answer": "The uterus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ded371ea2747c8aff16d48", "question": "What is the name of the cloud-riding, glasses-wearing koopa in the Super Mario Bros. series?", "answer": "Lakitu", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a5", "question": "What is the hobby of autograph collecting called?", "answer": "Philography", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6fd", "question": "What element on the Periodic Table is represented by the symbol \"Hg\"?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe1efcf145fb2946670738e", "question": "What is the Japanese art of flower arrangement called?", "answer": "Ikebana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a32a", "question": "Which character did Nick Nolte play in the 1982 film \"48 Hrs.\"?", "answer": "Jack Cates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abf2", "question": "In what sort of landscape would you find an erg?", "answer": "Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fed2bbaec223966ae8f8911", "question": "What is the name of the smelly green ghost in \"Ghostbusters\"?", "answer": "Slimer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6017379944491cbd7c5a178c", "question": "Which of ganster Al Capone's top lieutenants went by the nickname \"The Enforcer\"?", "answer": "Frank Nitti -- He became head of \"The Chicago Outfit\" after Capone went to prison. This is matter of dispute among historians.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc1e76de0eb824d4052e3", "question": "What islands make up the British Virgin Islands?", "answer": "The British Virgin Islands is a former colony that includes the islands of Virgin Gorda, Tortola, Anegada, and Jost Van Dyke.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff20f9c31a458464a93c435", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Yearling\"?", "answer": "Marjorie Kinnan Rawlings", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abe0", "question": "What is the capital of Tunisia?", "answer": "Tunis", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338977", "question": "Who is the last remaining survivor from Earth in \"The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy\"?", "answer": "Arthur Dent", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a25f2236682715b82711ce8", "question": "Feijoada, the national dish of Brazil, originates from which European country?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af10", "question": "What was the first American city to host the Summer Olympics?", "answer": "St. Louis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4b5cf06d333868d34d6ed", "question": "In the Bible, what man was sent to prepare the way for Jesus?", "answer": "John the Baptist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba37", "question": "What theme park did Dolly Parton open in Tennessee?", "answer": "Dollywood", "category": "general"}, {"id": "591c353e815febcc896f925a", "question": "Jakarta is located on which Indonesian island?", "answer": "Java", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b39f", "question": "Who is the inventor of the cash register?", "answer": "James Ritty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5937ed3d08d98002fdd633c7", "question": "What was Harry Houdini's birth name?", "answer": "Erik Weisz", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de1", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"zero\"?", "answer": "Arabic", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c68dfbde8045e48466b7", "question": "Dysmorphia is a mental disorder characterized by what?", "answer": "The obsessive idea that some aspect of one's own body part or appearance is severely flawed.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd19", "question": "What vegetable is found in dishes served \"Florentine\" style?", "answer": "Spinach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4bef49076251badbeaca", "question": "Which U.S. President had his sister initially serve as First Lady?", "answer": "Grover Cleveland -- \u00a0His sister Rose Cleveland took on the duties of First Lady until he married his bride Frances in June 1886.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4d990408b8581f80b092b2", "question": "What month in 2017 did North Korea fire a test missile across the Sea of Japan, prompting international condemnation?", "answer": "February", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339229", "question": "Who is pictured with her eyes wide open on posters for Kubrick's \"Eyes Wide Shut\" movie?", "answer": "Nicole Kidman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa74f73838c5c8a417f37", "question": "What is the fear of long words known as?", "answer": "Hippopotomostrosesquippedaliophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133951a", "question": "Who voiced Hades in the 1997 Disney movie \"Hercules\"?", "answer": "James Woods", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b76c", "question": "How many points is the outer white ring of an Olympic archery target worth?", "answer": "One", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a728c336bcd28c119383282", "question": "What is the name of Christopher Lee's autobiography?", "answer": "Tall, Dark and Gruesome", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b393", "question": "Who was the 35th President of the US?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "596760e52b59efe0e9417e9f", "question": "Panophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Everything", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b5717d767df192a942e3359", "question": "What significance does the number 4468 have to trainspotters?", "answer": "Marks the 4468 Mallard, the fastest steam locomotive", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0d2", "question": "What guitar player was the last act to perform at the original Woodstock in 1969?", "answer": "Jimi Hendrix", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febbcde7e83c707845b2152", "question": "Who played Dracula in the 1931 vampire-horror film \"Dracula\"?", "answer": "Bela Lugosi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f9f457caf848b908361b873", "question": "Who became president of Brazil in 2019?", "answer": "Jair Bolsonaro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bba3", "question": "What woman's name is the correct term for a female donkey?", "answer": "Jenny", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aea", "question": "The Christmas carol \"Jingle Bells\" was first published under what title?", "answer": "One Horse Open Sleigh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d2db2596a59cbdfbd394", "question": "The Iguazu Falls lie on the border of Brazil and which country?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339216", "question": "What fictional Kansas town is the earthly home of the young Superman?", "answer": "Smallville", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca3", "question": "Oliver Mellors was the proper name of what D.H. Lawrence title character?", "answer": "Lady Chatterley's Lover", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febaddb7e83c707845b20f4", "question": "Approximately, how much horsepower can one horse produce?", "answer": "15", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b23b", "question": "What royal subject married Sarah Ferguson?", "answer": "Prince Andrew", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b92d", "question": "What game has the winner striking the loser's wrist with two extended fingers?", "answer": "Rock, Paper, Scissors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb4b", "question": "What was the first brand of toothpaste to be sold in tubes rather than jars?", "answer": "Colgate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba4c", "question": "What college football championship game has been held in Miami since 1935?", "answer": "Orange Bowl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aae2", "question": "Khartoum is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b366", "question": "What nationality was the explorer Vitus Bering?", "answer": "Danish", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ab0", "question": "During the 1960's, what musician formed and fronted the band \"The Mothers of Invention\"?", "answer": "Frank Zappa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea42f7ff048f679a45ab7e", "question": "What is the sea parrot commonly known as?", "answer": "Puffin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339587", "question": "What movie earned Steven Spielberg his first Oscar?", "answer": "Schindler's List", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bcf", "question": "In Norse mythology who are the female attendants of Odin?", "answer": "The Valkyrie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be65", "question": "What is the more common name for a \"double-eagle\" on a gold hole?", "answer": "An albatross", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339595", "question": "In the film Moneyball who stars as the general manager of a struggling baseball team?", "answer": "Brad Pitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d99", "question": "What Paris-born actress returned to her hometown for the 2004 movie \"Before Sunset\"?", "answer": "Julie Delpy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c79f", "question": "Who is credited with the discovery of Neptune's moon, Triton?", "answer": "William Lassell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c54c", "question": "\"Consumption\" was the former name of what disease?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bbd4ceb00d154d7af00b8d3", "question": "Michael Stipe was the lead singer of which band?", "answer": "R.E.M.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c96", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Norwich, Vermont?", "answer": "Newhart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59da1b9ff6756c9b30ba14fb", "question": "Kiev is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Ukraine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592205cea4edfd43a087adea", "question": "Of which country did F.W. de Klerk become president in 1989?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac60", "question": "Which carved stone was the key to the understanding of Egyptian hieroglyphics?", "answer": "The Rosetta Stone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a217", "question": "Who was the first winner of the British version of the TV reality show \"Big Brother\"?", "answer": "Craig Phillips", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af7b", "question": "The USS Arizona Memorial commemorates the victims of what event?", "answer": "Japanese bombing of Pearl Harbor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015eb72fe83fe1f2a824bf8", "question": "The apostle Paul was called by Jesus on the road to which city?", "answer": "Damascus -- Paul was sent from Jerusalem to Damascus to arrest followers of Jesus.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4c9b49076251badbead8", "question": "Who was the first American to orbit the Earth?", "answer": "John Glenn -- He orbited the Earth three times in five hours in a Mercury space capsule he named \"Friendship 7\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a9e93d17ccba3ffe45786ca", "question": "What was Buddy Holly's real first name?", "answer": "Charles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396de", "question": "Which pop group was initially named \"The Pendletones\"?", "answer": "The Beach Boys", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f17ecee580c7f8fd1e50", "question": "Who said, \"Only the dead have seen the end of war.\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392a8", "question": "Whose California grave marker reads \"1935 - 1998 And the Beat Goes On?\"", "answer": "Sonny Bono's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa4a", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Delaware?", "answer": "Dover", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015ff61fe83fe1f2a824c4e", "question": "In 1948, which NBA basketball team did the Harlem Globetrotters defeat which eventually helped break the NBA's color barrier?", "answer": "Minneapolis Lakers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd96b2b23c87fd04dd15e18", "question": "In what language was the US Declaration of Independence first announced?", "answer": "German", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c197", "question": "Who led over 900 followers in a mass suicide in 1978?", "answer": "Jim Jones", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be31", "question": "How many players are there in a standard beach volleyball team?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac3f", "question": "What Roman god is January named for?", "answer": "Janus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c722", "question": "What company introduced the first hand-held calculator in 1967?", "answer": "Texas Instruments", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b34e", "question": "What was the nickname of the son of Cleopatra and Julius Caesar?", "answer": "Caesarion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0e5", "question": "Which pasta is shaped like a bicycle?", "answer": "Biciclette", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3bc", "question": "What is the common name for butterfly larvae?", "answer": "Caterpillars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe90a2201dd7bf43be5e896", "question": "The psychological test of human emotions and personality, using inkblots, is formally known as what?", "answer": "The Rorschach test", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abe2", "question": "Tunisia is part of which continent?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec8728ec223966ae8f8813", "question": "What is the astronomical event the astronauts travel through in the film \"Interstellar\"?", "answer": "A wormhole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe36ba60ada16518afdc03d", "question": "Which music mogul was involved in creating \"RocaWear\"?", "answer": "Jay-Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baac", "question": "What newspaper, founded in 1801, has been well known for its gossip column called \"Page Six\"?", "answer": "New York Post", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133923d", "question": "What track from U2's \"The Joshua Tree\" album won a Grammy for its video?", "answer": "Where the Streets Have No Name", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394d5", "question": "Which actor became famous thanks to his role in the 1986 film \"My Beautiful Laundrette\"?", "answer": "Daniel Day-Lewis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef92e66ce05a3942286e88", "question": "Who is the first mainstream artist known for utilizing the infamous Auto-Tune vocal distortion technique?", "answer": "Cher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338903", "question": "What Ian Fleming novel's title is the nickname of the character Francisco Scaramanga?", "answer": "The Man with the Golden Gun", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef5b466ce05a3942286e14", "question": "\"V-Bucks\" are the in-game currency for which famous videogame franchise?", "answer": "\"Fortnite\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b71d", "question": "Who eats Christpsomo when they return home from mass at 4 a.m. Christmas morning?", "answer": "Greek Christians", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3589675db0d66a186cb54b", "question": "Which popular artist was born as Robyn Fenty in 1988 in Barbados?", "answer": "Rihanna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb16e65ff7d326b622a6a", "question": "During which month is the longest day in the Southern hemisphere?", "answer": "December", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bbd4bc600d154d7af00b8ce", "question": "Which nu metal band released the songs \"My Way\" and \"Rollin'\"?", "answer": "Limp Bizkit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf30", "question": "What is the largest key on a standard computer keyboard?", "answer": "The Space Bar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f9bb01dd7bf43be5e84d", "question": "What was football legend Joe Namath's nickname?", "answer": "Broadway Joe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389ea", "question": "What is by far the most famous New York-based piece of work by French sculptor Auguste Bartholdi?", "answer": "The Statue of Liberty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d076f8870e6f05ba600860", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Taming of the Shrew\", who is the shrew's father?", "answer": "Baptista Minola", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c7", "question": "What was the first medication to be sold in the form of water-soluble tablets?", "answer": "Aspirin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c313", "question": "How many times a year does the sun rise and set at the North Pole?", "answer": "Once", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c665", "question": "Who performed the first human heart transplant?", "answer": "Dr. Chris Barnard", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8963ec223966ae8f8828", "question": "What was Harrison Ford's first credited feature film?", "answer": "\"A Time for Killing\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c596", "question": "Blacked eyed peas are not peas, what are they?", "answer": "Beans", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6000f14a9a72b906b34e3d03", "question": "What kind of animal is a bantam?", "answer": "Chicken -- A true bantam is a breed of chicken that is naturally small.  The male has a reputation for being very aggressive.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b540", "question": "What language was left unpunctuated until the modern age?", "answer": "Japanese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe768b9eec85e375820b2a6", "question": "What is the easternmost Caribbean country?", "answer": "Barbados", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d54", "question": "What famous double negative is the first line in Pink Floyd's \"Another Brick in the Wall (Part II)\"?", "answer": "We don't need no education", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab90", "question": "What was Cambodia once known as?", "answer": "Khmer Empire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c6", "question": "What was the name of the first manned mission to land on the Moon?", "answer": "Apollo 11", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c38f", "question": "What bird lays the largest eggs?", "answer": "The ostrich", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b361", "question": "Which planet was discovered in 1846?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5c436ce05a3942286e1e", "question": "When Michael Jordan played for the Chicago Bulls, how many NBA Championships did he win?", "answer": "6", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baa5", "question": "What country produces Angostura Bitters?", "answer": "Trinidad and Tobago", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3cd", "question": "What country is sometimes called the Land of Fire and Ice?", "answer": "Iceland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b1b0e662d71a53650fd2", "question": "Where was the graveyard located where Lord Voldemort made his return?", "answer": "Little Hangleton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b4", "question": "In Drop-D tuning, what is the lowest string of a guitar tuned down to?", "answer": "D", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffcfb3d9dc5ec6cd98a8315", "question": "Who painted the Mona Lisa?", "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe658a5ae7e414034b5aef4", "question": "Who became Romanian President after the 1989 Revolution?", "answer": "Ion Iliescu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b583", "question": "What year was the iPod first introduced?", "answer": "2001", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b32341abf195a31e15d73a2", "question": "What desert covers most of southern Mongolia?", "answer": "The Gobi desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c4", "question": "When did Indira Gandhi's first term as Prime Minister of India begin?", "answer": "1966", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb04", "question": "What was the original designation of the Pioneer 10 space probe?", "answer": "Pioneer F", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab977986faa38a764be529", "question": "On what vehicle was the Mutt Cutts Van based on in the 1994 film \"Dumb and Dumber\"?", "answer": "1984 Ford Econoline", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b820", "question": "What flavors make up Neopolitan ice cream?", "answer": "Vanilla, chocolate and strawberry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b7", "question": "What Dublin-born author won both a Nobel Prize and an Academy Award during his lifetime?", "answer": "George Bernard Shaw", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfde", "question": "How many tournaments make up a Grand Slam in golf?", "answer": "4\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69b8c20565ad31a57c760", "question": "What president turned down a scholarship to Harvard?", "answer": "Richard Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b9", "question": "What is a calorie a unit of?", "answer": "Energy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff14380b0ee8c595b6d39b2", "question": "Who wrote the 15th century novel \"The Tale of Two Lovers\"?", "answer": "Pope Pius II", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d9692596a59cbdfbd3c4", "question": "Who led the covert mission known as the Boston Tea Party?", "answer": "Samuel Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133905f", "question": "How old was poet Sylvia Plath when she committed suicide?", "answer": "30", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca71", "question": "What term is applied to animals or plants that are not nocturnal?", "answer": "Diurnal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339331", "question": "What western drama series told the story of Pat Garrett and Billy the Kid?", "answer": "The Tall Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2f5", "question": "What is the largest planet in the solar system?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab0e", "question": "Athens is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad0", "question": "Which author set most of his book in the year 802,701?", "answer": "H.G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c2", "question": "What is Albumen the correct term for?", "answer": "Egg White", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc0c", "question": "What year did Wayne Gretzky's professional hockey career start?", "answer": "1978", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b596", "question": "Which building has been nicknamed \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "GE Building", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391dd", "question": "Who played Mr. Orange in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Tim Roth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab1bb0baab681b0929219b", "question": "Which Canadian city is host to the Canadian International Autoshow?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f0b6ff048f679a45aaa4", "question": "Somniphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Sleep", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdf2", "question": "What word has Beyonce Knowles defined as \"beautiful, bountiful and bounce-able\"?", "answer": "Bootylicious", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a81c", "question": "What is the smallest independent country in Asia?", "answer": "Maldives", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ddd", "question": "Who reveals \"the man behind the curtain\" in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "Toto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65825ae7e414034b5aee8", "question": "Who was the husband of the female Judge Deborah in the Bible?", "answer": "Lapidoth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5963702f967692ea851899b8", "question": "What singer scored a #1 hit in 1999 with a duet with his wife, Lisa Hartman entitled, \"When I Said I Do\"?", "answer": "Clint Black", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab96fc86faa38a764be525", "question": "What car did Kowalski commit to delivering in the 1971 film \"Vanishing Point\"?", "answer": "Dodge Challenger (1970 Dodge Challenger R/T 440 Magnum, to be specific)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a509", "question": "Which country was formerly known as East Pakistan?", "answer": "Bangladesh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dcc", "question": "What double-word song title was a hit single by The Beau Brummels?", "answer": "Laugh Laugh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe25860658e585fda9cfa3f", "question": "Ceviche is made by marinating raw fish in what type of liquid?", "answer": "Lime juice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60077fd2bd51d85e222ab640", "question": "What was the official diagnosis when van Gogh was hospitalized in 1888?", "answer": "When Van Gogh was hospitalized on Christmas Eve 1888 in Ales, his official diagnosis was \"acute mania with generalised delirium\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f68", "question": "In 2006, what song became the first British single to top the US charts in almost a decade?", "answer": "You're Beautiful", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f16919f7c52aae91cc07cd", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Moonstone\"?", "answer": "Wilkie Collins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa54ccc73aa70ea0b70b1f", "question": "In what country are April Fool's jokes climaxed with the saying \"Doroughe sizdah\"?", "answer": "Iran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a06b", "question": "In which film did Donna Summer make her debut as an aspiring disco singer?", "answer": "Thank God It's Friday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e6", "question": "What year was writer Arthur C. Clarke born?", "answer": "1917", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6010c6220775fa611bce67cf", "question": "What was the original name of Chicago's Willis Tower?", "answer": "Sears Tower -- Sears Tower, the former home to Sears Roebuck and Company, was the tallest building in the world from 1973 to 1998.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae0d", "question": "Who was the first female commander of NASA's Space Shuttle?", "answer": "Eileen Collins", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b44b", "question": "On August 2, 1876, Jack McCall gunned down which famous lawman?", "answer": "Wild Bill Hickok", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133993a", "question": "Who voices the character of Bart Simpson on the TV show \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Nancy Cartwright", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f76", "question": "What was Tom Petty's backing band?", "answer": "The Heartbreakers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2fa", "question": "Where did tightrope artist Philippe Petit illegally walk on August 7, 1974?", "answer": "Between the World Trade Center towers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ae8629c7f28483af1e7fdc7", "question": "What country has the highest average rainfall in the world?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133933e", "question": "Which actress plays the role of Christine on the TV show \"Grey's Anatomy\"?", "answer": "Sandra Oh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c73f", "question": "How many pairs of chromosomes does the average human have?", "answer": "23", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b3", "question": "What is a parsec a unit of?", "answer": "Length", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ee", "question": "Which play was originally titled \"Mistakes of a Night\"?", "answer": "She Stoops to Conquer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdc121c469bb8041d07a07a", "question": "What popular diet cola soft drink first appeared in 1963?", "answer": "Tab", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda7", "question": "Whose emblem came from a sketch Lamar Hunt drew on a napkin in 1963?", "answer": "The Kansas City Chiefs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b126", "question": "What was the Italian word for the Jewish residential districts created during the middle ages?", "answer": "Ghetto", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf6a", "question": "What egyptian object is also known as \"The Key to the Nile\"?", "answer": "Ankh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bef4", "question": "What is the fear of parents-in-law known as?", "answer": "Soceraphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922a", "question": "What Welsh songstress has performed the themes for three different Bond movies?", "answer": "Shirley Bassey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a81", "question": "Edie Sedgwick was a protege of what artist?", "answer": "Andy Warhol", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab6f", "question": "What land feature separates Bangladesh from Nepal and Bhutan?", "answer": "Siliguri Corridor", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601601cffe83fe1f2a824c62", "question": "What does the star on the top of a Christmas tree symbolize?", "answer": "This is symbolic of the \"Star of Bethlehem\", the same star the Magi are said to have seen.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0cf", "question": "During the Civil War, what iron-clad ship engaged in battle with the \"CSS Virginia\"?", "answer": "The \"Monitor\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339234", "question": "What movie did Ewan McGregor get in character for by shaving his head and shedding 30 pounds?", "answer": "Trainspotting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d8", "question": "Which cartoon character had the vital statistics of 19-19-19?", "answer": "Olive Oyl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba48", "question": "What US city hosts the world's largest hot air balloon festival?", "answer": "Albuquerque", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398d3", "question": "What was the name of the Ewing's ranch on the TV series \"Dallas\"?", "answer": "Southfork", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a69220565ad31a57c7db", "question": "What was the name of British General Charles Cornwallis' dogs?", "answer": "Mars and Jupiter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd99", "question": "How many points is the red inner circle on a dartboard bull's-eye worth?", "answer": "Fifty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eda", "question": "What trumpet-like horn is jazz-man Chuck Mangione's instrument?", "answer": "The flugelhorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fa3", "question": "What nationality was the architect Le Corbusier?", "answer": "Swiss-French", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb3", "question": "Who was head coach of the Notre Dame college football team from 1918 to 1930?", "answer": "Knute Rockne", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe0da77fcbed638185eaa04", "question": "Which city has the world\u2019s largest network of aerial cable cars?", "answer": "La Paz, Bolivia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b6991b5e762b54eb9be941c", "question": "Into how many sectors is the standard dartboard divided into?", "answer": "20", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbcb", "question": "What religious movement was founded by Joseph Smith?", "answer": "Mormonism", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8eb", "question": "Graphite dust is formed when what is cut with a laser?", "answer": "Diamond", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca7e", "question": "What year did the US issue a patent on the production of margarine?", "answer": "1871", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd666faa5bfecdd737e0869", "question": "What is the busiest time of the year for air travel in the U.S.?", "answer": "Thanksgiving", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bbc91f660f0007efaba0e57", "question": "In which US state is it illegial to eat an orange in a bathtub?", "answer": "California", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b18c", "question": "What year did astronaut Neil Armstrong pass away?", "answer": "2012", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef96166ce05a3942286e9a", "question": "In what Disney movie would you find the character of Briar Rose?", "answer": "\"Sleeping Beauty\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062c98c9d816e292245c2d", "question": "What kind of cans did Andy Warhol famously paint?", "answer": "Campbell's Soup Cans\u00a0is a work of art consisting of 32 canvases, each painted with a Campbell's Soup can.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe3ed908b5801b8f54a7fb3", "question": "What biblical figure had a slave named Onesimus?", "answer": "Philemon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a752", "question": "The Black Hills, home to Mount Rushmore, are located in which US state?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51bddff04d658268c9311", "question": "In the Bible, who sold his birthright because he was hungry?", "answer": "Esau", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c77ccce24f0f7a362efd53f", "question": "What strait separates New Zealand's North and South Islands?", "answer": "Cook Strait", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae96", "question": "The 16th Constitutional Amendment, enacted in 1913 allowed the US federal government to do what?", "answer": "Tax personal income", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4afd49076251badbeabf", "question": "What was the first food to be intentionally microwaved?", "answer": "Popcorn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c330", "question": "What is known as the \"Droste Effect\"?", "answer": "The effect of an image appearing within itself", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a06", "question": "What D.H. Lawrence novel was originally titled \"Tenderness\"?", "answer": "Lady Chatterley's Lover", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391bd", "question": "What is Sean Connery's real first name?", "answer": "Thomas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b32a", "question": "Florence Nightingale tended the soldiers in which war?", "answer": "Crimean", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7c0", "question": "What area on the tip of South America has a name which translates as \"Land of Fire\"?", "answer": "Tierra del Fuego", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ec", "question": "What was the name of the mouse in the movie \"The Green Mile\"?", "answer": "Mr. Jingles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e97a9ebfabb9c85d8a965", "question": "Which popular beverage's name is German for \"storeroom\"?", "answer": "Lager", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338db3", "question": "What famous historical figure turns out to be the disguised Black Knight in Sir Walter Scott's \"Ivanhoe\"?", "answer": "Richard the Lion-hearted", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae0f", "question": "What city hosted the 2008 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "Beijing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394af", "question": "What was the name of the high school in which the TV show \"Room 222\" took place?", "answer": "Walt Whitman High", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eaa", "question": "What screen legend made her final appearance in the movie \"High Society\"?", "answer": "Grace Kelly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc5", "question": "Which detective story writer created the character Tuppence Beresford?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133896b", "question": "What is the better-known name of crime fiction writer Lady Mallowan D.B.E.?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abf8", "question": "In France what is a Framboise?", "answer": "Raspberry", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133930b", "question": "In Disney's movie \"The Lion King\", what does \"Hakuna Matata\" mean?", "answer": "No worries", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa57fbc73aa70ea0b70b37", "question": "Which U.S. state features the Italian phrase \"Fatti maschii, parole femine\" as its state motto?", "answer": "Maryland  (The motto translates as \u201cManly deeds, womanly words.\u201d\u00a0 The state uses\u00a0\"Strong deeds, gentle words\".)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c77cf8024f0f7a362efd54e", "question": "In \"The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time\", what are the names of the six races?", "answer": "Hylian, Kokiri, Goron, Zora, Gerudo, Shiekah.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf38", "question": "What is the Islamic equal to the Red Cross?", "answer": "Red Crescent", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec87eaec223966ae8f8819", "question": "Which Country won the Fed Cup consecutively, between 1976 and 1982?", "answer": "USA", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58bb34bfe368446ca7bd684b", "question": "Coffee beans come from which plant?", "answer": "Coffea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5d666ce05a3942286e2a", "question": "Which NFL teams always play on Thanksgiving Day?", "answer": "Detroit Lions and Dallas Cowboys", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133babe", "question": "What is the five-letter term for a rabbi who performs ritual circumcisions?", "answer": "Mohel", "category": "general"}]